http://uilab.kaist.ac.kr/members/dongwoo, +82.42.350.7749, dw.kim@kaist.edu

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in developing new machine learning models for computational science. More specifically, I'm interested in developing new latent variable models for analyzing and predicting the effect of online media on their audiences. During my masters and the Ph.D. program, I studied a subfield of machine learning called topic modeling and developed new variants of topic models to overcome the limitations of the basic parametric and nonparametric Bayesian topic models.

#### **EDUCATION**

KAIST, Ph.D., Computer Science, 2011 - 2014 (expected)

KAIST, M.S., Computer Science, 2011

Sung Kyun Kwan University, B.S., Computer Science, 2009

#### **EXPERIENCES**

Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA, USA, 2013 - 2013, Mentor: Nebojsa Jojic, Alessandro Perina

Research Intern, Microsoft Research Asia, Beijing, China, 2012 - 2012, Mentor: Haixun Wang

Research Intern, Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI), Daejeon, Republic of Korea, 2008 - 2008

## RECENT PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Dongwoo Kim, Haixun Wang, and Alice Oh. Context-dependent conceptualization. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-Third International Conference on Aritifical Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2013.
- [2] JinYeong Bak, Dongwoo Kim, and Alice Oh. Distributed online learning for latent dirichlet allocation. Workshop on Big Learning: Algorithms, Systems, and Tools at the NIPS. 2012., 2012.
- [3] Dongwoo Kim, Yeonseung Chung, and Alice Oh. Variable selection for latent dirichlet allocation. arXiv ePrints:1205.1053, 2012.
- [4] Dongwoo Kim, Suin Kim, and Alice Oh. Dirichlet process with mixed random measures: a nonparametric topic model for labeled data. In *Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)*, 2012.
- [5] Joon Hee Kim, Dongwoo Kim, Suin Kim, and Alice Oh. Modeling topic hierarchies with the recursive chinese restaurant process. In *Proceedings of the 21th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM)*, 2012.
- [6] Dongwoo Kim and Alice Oh. Accounting for data dependencies within a hierarchical dirichlet process mixture model. In *Proceedings of the 20th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM)*, 2011.
- [7] Dongwoo Kim and Alice Oh. Topic chains for understanding a news corpus. In *Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics (CICLING)*, 2011.
- [8] Dongwoo Kim, Yohan Jo, Il-Chul Moon, and Alice Oh. Analysis of twitter lists as a potential source for discovering latent characteristics of users. In Workshop on Microblogging at the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computer Systems, 2010.

Dongwoo Kim

[9] Il-Chul Moon, Dongwoo Kim, Yohan Jo, and Alice Oh. Learning influence propagation of personal blogs with content and network analyses. In 2010 IEEE Second International Conference on Social Computing (SocialCom), pages 669–674. IEEE, 2010.

# $\mathbf{AWARDS}$

Microsoft Research Fellowship Nomination Award, 2013

ICML Student Travel Scholarship, 2012